Sigmund Freud Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1871-1996 (Box 14-44)
  - Ferenczi, Sándor
    Microfilm edition of holdings at the Österreichisches Staatsarchiv, Vienna, Austria, 1908-1933 Shelf no. 19,042. See Appendix A for reel list
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1903, 1915, 1919
      - 1920-1921
      - 1924, undated
  - Feuchtwanger, Albert, 1918
  - Fields, Mary, 1927
  - Figdor, M. and Melanie, 1921-1931, 1938, undated
  - Finkelstein, M. N., 1916
  - Fischer-Colbrie, Arthur, 1916-1929
  - Fitzgerald, Gerald H., 1923
  - Fitzgerald-Lee, Gerald, 1938
  - Flatter, Richard, 1930-1932, 1939, 1951
  - Fleischer, Alexander, 1935
  - Fleischl, Ernst, 1884-1885
  - Fliess, Wilhelm (Box 26)
    Also available on microfilm. Shelf no. 18,025
    - 1887-1890
    - 1891-1892
    - 1893
      - Feb.-July
      - Aug.- Dec.
    - 1894
      - Jan.-June
      - July-Dec.
    - 1895
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-June
      - July-Sept.
      - Oct.-Dec.
    - 1896
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-May
      - June-Sept.
      - Oct.-Dec. See also Oversize
    - 1897
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.-Apr. See also Oversize
      - May-June
      - July-Sept. (Box 27)
      - Oct.
      - Nov.-Dec.
    - 1898
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-May
      - June-Aug.
      - Sept.-Oct.
      - Nov.-Dec.
    - 1899
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-June
      - July-Aug.
      - Sept.-Oct.
      - Nov.-Dec.
    - 1900
      - Jan.-Feb.
      - Mar.-Apr.
      - May-July
      - Sept.-Nov. (Box 28)
    - 1901
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - May-Aug.
      - Sept.-Dec.
    - 1902
    - 1904
  - Fliess, Wilhelm and Ida, photocopies and transcripts of Freud letters at University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Israel, 1892-1897, 1904, 1928-1929, with note by Peter Swales, undated
  - Flournoy, Henri, 1924-1938
  - Fluss, Emil, including comments and manuscript by Ernst L. Freud
    - 1872, 1969
    - 1873
    - 1874, 1886
  - Fodor, Nandor, 1938
  - Fondation Curie, Paris, France, 1939
  - Foulkes, S. H., 1932-1936, undated
  - Fox, Howard, 1939
  - Foxe, Arthur Norman, 1938
  - Fraenkel, Sigmund, 1933-1939
  - Frankl, Ludwig August, 1886
  - Franzos, Emil, to J. F. Bergmann, 1911
  - Frazer, Quintin, 1935, with essays regarding Daniel Paul Schreber case, undated
  - Freud, Vilém, 1939
  - Freund, Emil, 1911
  - Freund, Roszi, 1918, 1921
  - Friedjung, Heinrich, 1904
  - Friedjung, Josef Karl, 1925-1931, with letter from Anna Freud, 1939
  - Friends of the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1938
  - Frink, Horace Westlake and Angelika, 1921-1923
  - Frölich, Otto, 1932
  - Fuchs, Georg, 1933, undated
  - Fuchs, Heinz See same container, Foulkes, S. H.
  - Fülöp-Miller, René, 1938
  - Gaucher, André, 1925
  - Geraci, Francesco, 1933
  - Gildesgame, Pierre, 1938
  - Glanz, Heinrich and Selma, 1917, 1919, 1936, 1939
  - Glover, Edward, undated
  - Glücksmann, Heinrich, 1935, 1937
  - Goetzel, Mrs. A.
    - 1918-1928
    - 1929-1937
  - Gomperz, Elise, 1901, 1913, undated See also same container, Gomperz, Theodor and Elise
  - Gomperz, Heinrich, 1898-1899, 1912-1913, 1920-1933
  - Gomperz, Theodor and Elise, 1908, 1913, 1931 See also same container, Gomperz, Elise
  - Graun, Richard E., 1922
  - Greene, John G., 1934, with cover letter from him to Ernest Jones, 1956
  - Greminger, Marthy, 1936-1937
  - Grinker, Roy R., 1920, 1933-1939 (Box 29)
  - Groddeck, Georg, 1921
  - Gropper, Mrs. Jerome, 1930
  - Grotjahn, Martin, 1938
  - Gruen, Oscar, 1925, with cover letter from Arthur Charlap-Hyman to K. R. Eissler, 1977
  - Guilbert, Yvette, 1894, 1926-1938, undated
  - Gutscher, Alma, 1933
  - Häberlin, Carl, 1927, 1929
  - Häberlin, Paul, 1910-1913
  - Hale, William Bayard, 1922
  - Hall, G. Stanley
    - Originals and miscellaneous photocopies, 1908-1913
    - Photocopies from Clark University Library, Worcester, Mass., 1908-1923
  - Haller, Maggie, 1910-1914
  - Hammerschlag, Anna, 1933
  - Hammerschlag, Bertha, 1936
  - Hammerschlag, Betty, 1905
  - Hammerschlag, Samuel, 1885
  - Happel, Clara, 1926
  - Harlow, Arthur, 1938
  - Harris, Mrs. Maurice, 1933
  - Harrit, Mamie M., 1922
  - Hartmann, Heinz, photocopies, 1927-1939 See also Container 138, Hartmann, Heinz, originals
  - Hartzfeld, Carstus Albertus Jacobus, 1939
  - Hasenclever, Walter, 1917, 1932, 1938, with letters from [?] Witzleiben to K. R. Eissler, 1969
  - Healy, William, 1929
  - Hebrew Teachers' Association, 1928-1932
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Palestine, 1935, 1938
  - Heilbronner, P., 1938
  - Heilpern, Else, 1937
  - Heilpern, Grete, 1930-1937
  - Heller, Victor See Container 12, Heller, Judith Bernays and Victor
  - Hellpach, Willy, 1903-1905
  - Hérenger, Alexandre, 1929-1930, 1936
  - Hering, Helene, 1931
  - Hermann, Imre, 1933
  - Herring, Mr. [?], 1938
  - Herzfeld, Ernst, 1930
  - Herzfeld, Marie, 1932
  - Herzl, Theodor, 1902
  - Hesse, Hermann, 1918, 1936
  - Hessing, Siegfried, 1933
  - Hill, John C., 1928, 1936, with cover letter from Rudolf Ekstein to K. R. Eissler, 1966
  - Hillebrand, Grete, 1929
  - Hiller, Eric, 1922
  - Hiller, Kurt, 1936, 1938
  - Hinterberger, Heinrich, 1928
  - Hirschfeld, Magnus, 1906 See also Container 25, Fackel-Kraus
  - Hitschmann, Eduard
    - Originals, 1905, 1916
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1908-1918
      - 1919-1936, undated
  - Hitschmann, Hedwig, 1925
  - Hobman, Daisy L., 1939
  - Hoffman, D., 1932
  - Hollòs, Istvàn, 1928, 1933
  - Holstijn, A. J. Westerman, 1926, with letter from him to K. R. Eissler, 1954
  - Hölzer-Weineck, Irene, 1931-1936
  - Hoop, J. H. van der, circa 1931, 1937 (Box 30)
  - Hooper, Franklin Henry, 1924
  - Hopf, Ludwig, 1925-1936
  - Hoppe-Moser, Fanny, 1918, with letter from Ola Andersson to Ernst L. Freud, 1965
  - Hopper, Charles W., 1938
  - Horn, Jaroslav, 1936
  - Howard, Samuel, 1934
  - Huberman, Mrs. Jacob, 1899
  - Hughes, Randolph, 1939
  - Hurvitz, Rosetta, 1926
  - Indra, Alfred, 1938
  - Institute of Psycho-analysis, London, England, 1938
  - International Psycho-Analytical Association
    - 1920-1922
    - 1924-1936
  - Internationale Psychoanalytische Zeitschrift, 1933, with letter from Max M. Stern to K. R. Eissler, 1959
  - Internationaler Pschoanalytischer Verlag, 1922, undated
  - Irzykowski, Karl, undated, with letter from [?] Makeck, 1939
  - Izeddin, Dr. [?], 1938
  - Jackson, Edith Banfield, 1929-1936, undated
  - Jackson, Josephine A., 1938
  - Jaffe, L., 1935
  - James, William, 1909
  - Jankélévitch, S., 1911, 1920-1921, 1926, 1930
  - Jekels, Ludwig
    - Originals, 1909-1911, 1924
    - Photocopies
      - 1909-1917
      - 1920-1921
      - 1922-1923
      - 1924-1928, undated
  - Jelgersma, Gerbrandus, 1929
  - Jelliffe, Smith Ely, 1938-1939
  - Jerusalem, Wilhelm, 1908
  - Jewish community in the Argentine, 1938
  - Jodl, Friedrich, 1904-1905
  - Jones, Ernest
    - Originals
      - 1908-1910
      - 1911
      - 1912
      - 1913 (Box 31)
      - 1914
      - 1915-1919
      - 1920
      - 1921
      - 1922
      - 1923
      - 1924-1925
      - 1926-1927
      - 1928-1929
      - 1930-1931
      - 1932-1933
      - 1934-1936 (Box 32)
      - 1937-1939
    - Transcripts, 1910-1939
  - Jordan, Rachel, 1921
  - Jung, C. G.
    - From Freud
      - Originals
        Also available on microfilm. Shelf no. 16,576
        - 1906
        - 1907
          - Jan.-Apr.
          - May-July
          - Aug.-Dec.
        - 1908
          - Jan.-Mar.
          - Apr.-July
          - Aug.-Dec.
        - 1909
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1910
          - Jan.-Apr.
          - May-Aug.
          - Sept.-Dec.
        - 1911
          - Jan.-Mar.
          - Apr.-July
          - Aug.-Oct.
          - Nov.-Dec.
        - 1912
          - Jan.-Mar.
          - Apr.-Dec.
        - 1913
      - Transcripts
        - 1906
        - 1907 (Box 33)
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1908
          - Jan.-Mar.
          - Apr.-July
          - Aug.-Dec.
        - 1909
        - 1910
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1911
          - Jan.-Aug.
          - Sept.-Dec.
        - 1912-1913
    - To Freud
      - Photocopies
        - 1906
        - 1907
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1908
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1909 (Box 34)
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1910
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1911
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1912
          - Jan.-May
          - June-Dec.
        - 1913, 1923
      - Transcripts
        - 1906
        - 1907
          - Jan.-May
          - June-Dec.
        - 1908
          - Jan.-May
          - June-Dec.
        - 1909
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1910
          - Jan.-June
          - July-Dec.
        - 1911 (Box 35)
          - Jan.-May
          - June-Dec.
        - 1912
          - Jan.-May
          - June-Dec.
        - 1913, 1923
  - Jung, Emma
    - 1910
    - 1911-1912
  - Kainz, Joseph, 1900-1903, undated
  - Kallir, Dr. [?], 1936-1937
  - Kanter, Abraham Herbert, 1938
  - Kaplan, Leo, 1915-1922
  - Kaplan, Moses, 1918
  - Kardiner, Abram, 1921, 1932
  - Karpe, Marietta, 1935
  - Kassowitz, Karl Erhard, 1899
  - Katan, Mauritz, 1937, with letter from Anna Freud to K. R. Eissler, 1958
  - Kaufman, Freda, 1928
  - Kaye, Kamen, 1932
  - Kayy, W. H. (William Howard Kupper), 1938
  - Kemper, W., 1933
  - Kempny, Hedy, 1933
  - Kennamore, Mr. [?], 1927
  - Kerpel, Edmund, undated
  - Kerpel, Eugen, 1933, 1939
  - Keyserling, Hermann, Graf von, 1925, 1932
  - Kluge, Walter, 1929
  - Knopf, Blanche W., 1939
  - Knöpfmacher, Wilhelm, 1878
  - Kohn, Otto, 1932, with letter from Henry H. Kay to Anna Freud, 1970
  - Koller, Carl
    - Originals with transcripts, 1885, undated
    - Photocopies, transcripts, and cover letter from Hortense K. Becker to Ruth Eissler
      - 1880-1885, 1975
      - 1886-1887, undated
  - Königstein, Leopold, 1909
  - Kosawa, Heisaku
    - 1925, 1931-1932
    - 1933, 1935, undated
  - Kossmann, Max, 1939
  - Krafft, Margaret R., 1928, 1931, 1936 See also Container 54, Eissler, K.R.
  - Kramer, H., 1928
  - Krapf, E. Eduardo, 1937
  - Kraus, Karl, 1904-1906
  - Krauss, Friedrich S., 1910
  - Krausz, Wilhelm Victor, 1936
  - Krimberg, E., 1928
  - Kris, Ernst and Marianne, 1930-1931, 1937, undated
  - Kriser, Rudolf, 1911-1917
  - Kronenzeitung, 1927
  - Kubie, Lawrence S., 1936
  - Kvergic-Kraus, Gertrude, 1936-1938
  - Lach, Robert, 1928, 1931
  - Lackner, Stephan, 1937
  - Laforgue, René, 1923-1929 (Box 36)
  - Lampl, Hans, and Jeanne Lampl-de Groot, 1938-1939 See also same container, Lampl-de Groot, Jeanne
  - Lampl, Otto, 1931
  - Lampl-de Groot, Jeanne See also same container, Lampl, Hans
    - 1921-1925
    - 1926-1929
    - 1931
    - 1932
      - Jan.-May
      - June-Dec.
    - 1933
    - 1937-1938
  - Lancaster, Elizabeth G., with draft of her “The Dreams of the Traumatic Neuroses,” 1930-1936, undated
  - Lancet, 1938
  - Landman, Isaac, 1929, with note by William G. Niederland, undated
  - La Posea, Charlotte W., 1929
  - League of American Writers, 1938-1939
  - Lederer, Josie P., 1938
  - Lehrman, Philip Raphael, 1926-1936
  - Leitner, Z. A., 1939
  - Leroy, Maxine, 1937
  - Levarie, Siegmund, 1931
  - Levin, Abraham J., 1938
  - Levy, Kata
    - 1918-1920
    - 1921-1926, undated
  - Levy, Lájos, 1918, 1925
  - Levy, Willi, 1937-1938
  - Levy-Suhl, Max, 1930
  - Lewinson, Jochanan B., 1936
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig, 1927
  - Leyens, Erich, 1923, 1936
  - Liebman, Julius, 1925-1932
  - Lindenberg, Therese, 1930
  - Lipschütz, Alejandro, 1927, 1931, with letter from him to Fischer Verlag, 1975
  - Locker Lampson, Oliver, 1938
  - Loewbeer, Mr. [?], 1923
  - Loewenstein, Rudolph M., 1926-1927
  - Looney, J. Thomas, 1938
  - Lorand, Sándor, 1928
  - Lorenz, Emil, 1911, 1932
  - Lovell, Roger A. J., 1939
  - Low, David, 1938, with letter to Ernst L. Freud, 1956
  - Löwenstein, Hubertus, Prinz zu, 1938-1939
  - Löwy, Emanuel, 1905
  - Löwy, Heinrich, 1930
  - Luschnat, David, 1939
  - Maccabi World Union, 1939 (Box 37)
  - Mackenzie, William, 1920, with letter from Emilio Servadio to Anna Freud, 1958
  - Mackworth, Margaret Haig Thomas, Viscountess Rhondda, 1938 See also Container 42, Time and Tide
  - Maeder, Alfonse
    - 1910-1911
    - 1912-1914
  - Magarik, Isidore, 1938
  - Magnes, Judah Leon, 1931-1935
  - Maitlis, Jacob J., 1938
  - Malinowski, Bronislaw, 1938
  - Mann, Thomas, 1930-1939
  - Mannes, Elisabeth, 1911-1917
  - Marcondes, Durval, 1920, 1926-1933, undated
  - Marcuse, Max, 1908-1910
  - Marshall, Lenore G., 1930
  - Marui, Kiyoyasu, 1927-1931, with letter from him to K. R. Eissler, 1952
  - Matte-Blanco, Ignacio, 1939
  - Mayer, Felix, 1936
  - Mayer, Louis, 1938-1939
  - Mayer-Gallin, Emilia, 1929, 1936-1937
  - Meller, Josef, 1934, with correspondence between Ernst L. Freud and Ilona de Suto Nagy, 1959
  - Mendelsohn, Benjamin, 1934-1938, with cover letter, 1947
  - Meng, Heinrich, 1920-1939, undated See also Container 41, Schmitz, Oskar A. H.
  - Menninger, Karl, 1937
  - Meyer, Max, 1923
  - Meyerson, Ignace, 1922
  - Michel, Dr. [?], 1930-1931
  - Moellenhoff, Fritz, 1933
  - Monod-Herzen, Edouard, 1923, 1926
  - Montaño, Garcia, 1934
  - Montessori, Maria, 1927
  - Mookerjee, S. P., 1938
  - Moravia, Freiberg See Container 38, Príbor Stadt
  - Mordell, Albert, 1920
  - Morichau-Beauchant, René, 1913
  - Morselli, Enrico Agostino, 1926
  - Mosonyi, Dezsö, 1929, with letter from Pierre Mosonyi to Anna Freud, 1972
  - Mühsam, Erich, 1907
  - Müller-Braunschweig, Carl, 1935-1937, with letter from Edith Weigert to K. R. Eissler, 1971
  - Munro, Adèle, 1938
  - Murray, Henry Alexander, 1932
  - Muthmann, Arthur, 1907, undated, with cover letter from Hans-Otto Muthmann to Sigmund Freud Archives, 1974
  - Nachmanson, Max, 1915
  - Nacht, Dr. [Sacha?], 1912, with letter from Martin Wangh to Harold P. Blum, 1989
  - Naesgaard, Sigurd, 1933
  - Neuberger, Max See Container 66, Schönbauer, L.
  - Neue Revue, 1908
  - Neumann, Robert, 1939
  - Neumann-Bernfeld, Liese, 1933
  - New York Neurological Society, New York, N.Y., 1936
  - Niels Kuppermann's Verlag, 1931
  - Nussenblatt, Tulo, 1938
  - Oberholzer, Emil
    - 1912-1919
    - 1920
    - 1921-1927, 1936
  - Oberholzer, Mirra, 1927-1931, undated (Box 38)
  - Oberndorf, Clarence P., 1909, 1917, 1927, undated
  - Oberstabsarzt, Etappenlazarett 6 Armee, notice concerning wounding of Max Halberstadt in battle, 1916
  - Ohtski, Kenji, 1932-1938
  - Olden, Rudolf, 1931
  - Opffer, Ivan, 1937-1938
  - Oppenheim, D. E., 1909
  - Oppenheim, Martha, 1930
  - Ossipow, Nikolai, 1921-1929, undated
  - Pailthorpe, Grace W., 1933
  - Pankejeff, Sergius, 1912-1930
  - Pantheon (envelope only), 1931
  - Paquet, Alfons, 1930
  - Paret, Peter, 1933
  - Paul-Schiff, Maximilian, 1929, 1936, with letter from Johanna Wertheimstein to K. R. Eissler, 1968
  - Penrose, L. S., 1931
  - Pereira da Silva, Gastão, 1934
  - Perlberger, Josef, 1930
  - Perleberg, Gilbert, 1933
  - Perlman, N., 1939
  - Pertinax, Johann, 1930
  - Petrikovitch, Edward, 1928, undated
  - Pfister, Oskar
    - 1909-1910
    - 1911-1913
    - 1918-1920
    - 1921-1924
    - 1925-1927
    - 1928-1940
  - Pichler, Hans, 1938
  - Pichler, K. R. von, 1912
  - Pick, Alois, 1926, 1936
  - Pilz, Robert, 1927
  - Pollak, Isidor, 1937
  - Pollak, Max, 1927-1935
  - Popescu, Ioan I., 1927-1934
  - Popper-Lynkeus, Josef, 1916-1917
  - Proctor-Gregg, Nancy, 1938
  - Pötzl, Otto, 1917, 1919, 1937
  - Powers, Lillian Delger, 1925, undated
  - Premsela, M. J., 1927
  - Presidents of psychoanalytic associations, 1932
  - Príbor Stadt, Czechoslovakia (formerly Freiberg, Moravia), 1931
  - Pribram, Alfred Francis, 1927-1929, 1935
  - Prince, Morton, 1905-1909
  - Protze, H., 1917
  - Putnam, Imarita, 1932-1933, undated
  - Putnam, James Jackson
    - 1909-1911
    - 1912-1913
    - 1914-1916
  - Querido, Arie, 1922, 1928
  - Quitman, Jesse, 1922
  - Rabka, Hanna Zucker von, 1938
  - Radó, Sándor (Box 39)
    - 1925-1928
    - 1929-1932
  - Rank, Otto
    - Originals, 1927, 1937
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      - 1905-1916
      - 1921-1922
      - 1923
      - 1924-1925
  - Reading room of Jewish high school, Vienna, Austria, 1911
  - Redlich, Kurt von, 1926
  - Reich, Wilhelm, 1924-1935
  - Reichlin, Henry, 1930
  - Reik, Theodor
    - Originals
      - 1912-1916
      - 1918-1922
      - 1923-1928
      - 1929-1932
      - 1934-1938, undated
    - Photocopies, 1929, 1939
    - Transcripts, translations, and publications
      - By others
        - 1912-1918
        - 1919-1928
        - 1929-1938, undated
      - By Reik, 1958-1962
  - Reisen, Salman, and Max Weinreich, 1930 See also Container 43, Weinreich, Max
  - Reitler, Rudolf, 1917
  - Relgis, Eugen, 1929-1930
  - Renz, Carl, 1914-1915
  - Révész, Eugen, 1918
  - Rickman, John, 1920-1938
  - Rie, Oscar, 1920-1923, 1929, 1931
  - Riese, Walter, 1926 (Box 40)
  - Riess, Hanna, 1934
  - Riethof, Adele, 1931
  - Rilke, Rainer Maria, 1916
  - Rischawy, Marie, 1926
  - Riviere, Joan
    - 1921-1922
    - 1923
    - 1924-1926
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929-1939
  - Roback, A. A., with cover letters from Roback to Ernest Jones, 1956
    - 1930-1938, 1956
    - 1934-1936
    - 1938-1939, undated
  - Robinson, Alice, 1927
  - Róheim, Géza, 1929
  - Rolland, Romain, 1923-1937
  - Rosenbach, Mr. [?], 1932
  - Rosenbacher, Richard, 1936
  - Rosenfeld, Eva, 1929-1930, 1937, with cover note by her, 1956
  - Rosenfeld, Rose, 1935-1938
  - Rosenmann, Marjan, 1930
  - Rosenzweig, Saul, 1934, 1937
  - Rubin, Mr. [?], 1930
  - Ruiz-Castillo, Miguel, 1920-1922
  - Sachs, Barnard, 1938, with cover letter from Helen Sachs Straus to K. R. Eissler, 1957, undated
  - Sachs, Hanns
    - From Freud, 1918, 1928-1930
    - To Freud
      - 1911-1913
      - 1914-1916
      - 1917-1918
      - 1919-1920
      - 1921-1928
      - 1929-1939, undated
  - Sachs, Wulf, 1930-1933
  - Sadger, Isidor, 1902
  - Salomon, F. G., 1931
  - Sarasin, Philipp, 1926-1929
  - Sarkar, Sarasi Lat, 1928
  - Sarnette, Eric-André, 1932
  - Saussure, Raymond de, 1922-1928, 1938
  - Schaeffer, Albrecht
    - From Freud, 1939
    - To Freud, 1928-1939
  - Scheu-Riesz, Helene, 1930 (Box 41)
  - Schilder, Paul, 1935, with cover material, 1955
  - Schiller, Max, 1938
  - Schloessinger, Max, 1931
  - Schmitz, Oskar A. H., and Heinrich Meng, 1920-1939 See also Container 37, Meng, Heinrich
  - Schnier, Jacques, 1936-1938
  - Schnierer, T., 1938
  - Schnitzler, Arthur
    - Photocopies and transcripts, 1906, 1912, 1922-1931, undated
    - Published edition of Freud letters to Schnitzler, 1906-1931, with additional background letters from Anna Freud, Ernest Jones, and others, 1953-1955
  - Schönberg, Ignaz, 1885, undated
  - Schulhof, Mimi, 1929
  - Schur, Max
    - Originals with transcript, 1930, 1938
    - Photocopies and transcripts, 1926-1939, undated
  - Schwadron, Abraham, 1923, 1936
  - Schwarz, Arthur, circa 1885
  - Schweitzer, Albert, 1936
  - Schwiedland, E., 1925, 1930
  - Schwutzer, Ferdinand, 1926
  - Seif, Leonhard, 1911, 1913
  - Seldes, George, 1924
  - Seward, Albert C., 1938
  - Shears, A. H., 1938
  - Silberer, Herbert, 1922
  - Silberstein, Eduard
    - Originals
      - Set A
        Also available on microfilm. Shelf no. 19,439
        - 1871
        - 1872
          - Jan.-Aug.
          - Sept.
        - 1873
        - 1874
          - Jan.-Aug.
          - Sept.-Oct.
          - Nov.-Dec.
        - 1875
          - Jan.-Feb.
          - Mar.-Apr.
          - May-Aug.
          - Sept.-Oct.
        - 1876
        - 1877-1881, 1910
        - Undated
      - Set B, 1873-1880
    - Photographs, undated
    - Translations, 1873-1880
  - Simmel, Ernst (Box 42)
    - 1918-1926
    - 1927-1928
    - 1929-1931
    - 1934-1939, undated
  - Spencer, Daisy, 1939
  - Stärcke, August
    - Originals and photocopies, 1912-1922
    - Transcripts, 1912-1922
  - Stärcke, Johann, 1912-1915
  - Steil, Jacob, 1932
  - Steiner, Maximilian, 1939
  - Steinig, Léon, 1932, undated For additional material see Container 21, Einstein, Albert, Related correspondence
  - Steinthal, Walter, 1939
  - Stekel, Wilhelm
    - 1904-1905, 1910-1911
    - 1912-1915, 1924, 1931, 1938, undated
  - Stendig, Samuel, 1938-1939
  - Stephani-Cherbuliez, Jeanne, 1933-1939
  - Sterba, Richard, 1932, 1939
  - Stern, Karl, 1935, with cover letter from Stern to K. R. Eissler, 1953
  - Stern, William, 1931
  - Stiassny, Frau Baurat, 1910
  - Stites, Raymond Somers, 1925
  - Stonborough-Wittgenstein, Margarethe, 1937-1939
  - Storfer, A. J., 1932
  - Strachey, James, 1928
  - Struck, Hermann
    Partially available on microfilm. Shelf no. 12,110.1
    - 1914-1929
    - 1916-1929
  - Sun, Joe Tom (pseudonym of a Dr. Thompson, Baltimore, Md.), 1923
  - Sweet, Norman, 1938
  - Sweetser, Arthur and Ruth, 1927-1928
  - Swoboda, Hermann, 1906
  - Szabó, Alexander, 1916-1921
  - Szabó, Szerena, 1916-1921
  - Tandler, Julius, 1925, 1931
  - Tannenbaum, Samuel Aaron, 1914, 1920
  - Teirich, Valentin, 1922, 1923
  - Teller, Frieda, 1914
  - Tenenblatt, A. M., 1925
  - Thayer, Scofield, 1925
  - Thieberger, Friedrich, 1926
  - Thoman, Maria, 1934
  - Thompson, Dr. [?] See same container, Sun, Joe Tom
  - Time and Tide, 1938 See also Container 37, Mackworth, Margaret Haig Thomas, Viscountess Rhondda
  - Tinty, Karl Ferdinand, 1934
  - Toczek, Mr. [?], 1937
  - Toeplitz and Deuticke, 1885-1887, 1910, 1918
  - Trotter, Wilfred, 1938
  - Tucholsky, Kurt, 1913
  - Twersky, Jochanan, 1939
  - Ullstein-Verlag, 1926
  - United States consul, Vienna, Austria, concerning family of Suzanne Bernfeld Cassirer, 1936
  - University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Palestine, 1936
  - University of Vienna, Vienna, Austria, Medical Dekanat, 1906, 1936
  - Urbantschitsch, Rudolf von, 1916, 1923-1928, 1952
  - Velikovsky, Immanuel, 1922, 1931-1933 (Box 43)
  - Vest, Anna von, 1903-1926
  - Vienna, Austria, city of, 1924
  - Viereck, George Sylvester
    - Originals with transcripts, 1923-1929
    - Photocopies and transcripts
      Partially available on microfilm. Shelf no. 9,781.1
      - 1919-1927
      - 1928
      - 1929-1936
  - Vogel, David, 1924
  - Voigtländer, Else, 1911, with background statement by Bernard L. Pacella, 1956
  - Vollmer, Herman, 1929
  - Wackernagel, Peter, 1927
  - Wadler, Louise and Robert, 1938, with statements by Louise Wadler Lambert and Alexander S. Rogawski, 1959
  - Wagner-Jauregg, Julius von, 1916-1919, 1932-1937, undated For additional material see Container 66, Schönbauer, L.
  - Walder, Robert, 1938
  - Wallach, Sidney, 1928
  - Walther, Gerda, 1935
  - Watermann, August, 1933
  - Webster, Doris, 1936
  - Wechsler, Israel Spanier, 1927-1938
  - Weigert, Edith, 1937-1939, undated, with letter from her to K. R. Eissler, 1971
  - Weinreich, Max, 1929, 1931 See also Container 39, Reisen, Salman
  - Weiss, Edoardo with commentary by him, circa 1965
    - 1919-1923
    - 1924-1930
    - 1931-1932
    - 1933-1939, undated
  - Weissmann, Karl, 1938
  - Wells, H. G., 1938-1939
  - Werfel, Franz, 1926, with cover letter to Ernst L. Freud, 1970
  - Wheeler, Mr. [?], 1929
  - Wheelock, Bertha, 1936
  - Wiener Psychoanalytische Vereinigung, 1907
  - Wilczeck, Gabriele Gräfin, 1931, 1937
  - Wilder, Thorton, 1936
  - Wilson, John C., 1938
  - Winterstein, Alfred, 1911-1915, 1924-1936
  - Wittels, Fritz, with letter from Poldi Goetz-Wittels to K. R. Eissler
    - 1921-1927, 1952
    - 1928-1935
  - Wittkowski, Victor, 1933-1937 (Box 44)
  - Wolff, Charlotte, 1937, with cover letter from Wolff to K. R. Eissler, 1971
  - Woolf, Leonard, 1939
  - Worrall, Ralph, 1937
  - Worsley, Allan, 1938
  - Wulf, Mosheh, 1932-1933
  - Yiddishen Wissenschaftlichen Institut, 1929-1930, 1936
  - Young, Dr. [?], 1928
  - Zweig, Adam, 1938